wjscore.com 2017-06-06

# Woodcock Assessment and Intervention Suite

                      Woodcock Assessment and Intervention Suite
                                            Privacy Policy
This Privacy Policy describes HMH’s collection, use, and sharing of information associated with
the HMH online assessment platform (“"the Product”) made available through this website (the
“website” or “site”). “You” and “Your” refer to anyone using the Product via our site. Use of the
Product entails Your submission of Submitted Data (as that term is defined below) as well as our
passive collection of technical and other information in connection with Your use of the Product
and the site. This Privacy Policy applies to the Product and the site, regardless of how You
access the Product, whether via personal computers, mobile devices, or otherwise.
To the extent particular information qualifies as Protected Health Information (PHI) under the
Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (“HIPAA”) and HIPAA affords greater
privacy protections than those set forth in this Privacy Policy, HMH will comply with the
relevant HIPAA requirements regarding privacy for that particular information.
1.      Definitions
De-Identified Information. The term “De-Identified Information” means information that meets
each of the following criteria: the information (i) does not identify a particular natural person; (ii)
does not identify, by network Internet Protocol address, raw hardware serial number, or raw
MAC address, a particular device or computer associated with or used by a person; (iii) does not
identify the school or natural person at issue by name or address; and (iv) is not reasonably
linkable to a particular natural person or school because of technical, legal, or other controls.
FERPA. The term “FERPA” means the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act, 20 USC
§1232g, and the Protection of Pupil Rights Amendment (“PPRA”), including associated
regulations.
HIPAA. The term “HIPAA” means the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act, 42
U.S.C. §§ 1320d et seq., and the Health Information Technology for Economic and Clinical
Health Act (the “HITECH Act”), including associated regulations under HIPAA and the
HITECH Act.
Nonpersonal Information. The term “Nonpersonal Information” refers to information that is
not Personal Information.
Personal Information. The term “Personal Information” refers to information that identifies a
particular person, such as first and last name, social security number, e-mail address, phone
number, and residential street address.
Relevant Information Security Standards. The term “Relevant Information Security
Standards” means the higher information security standards required under either (i) FERPA, or
(ii) HIPAA.

Submitted Data. The term “Submitted Data” means any information You provide to HMH in
connection with Your use of the Product including, but not limited to, information about
examinees. The term “Submitted Data” expressly excludes De-Identified Information.
Usage Information. The term “Usage Information” means information that does not directly
identify a particular person, but that may be linkable to a particular computer, device, operating
system, platform, or software instance (via a unique device ID or otherwise).
2.       Information We Collect
Information You Provide to Us. We collect the Submitted Data You provide. Depending on
what You provide, Submitted Data generally includes both Personal Information and
Nonpersonal Information about You as well as about examinees.
Information We Passively Collect. In addition to the information You actively provide, we also
passively collect Usage Information to help enable the functionality of the Product as an online
service and to help us improve and maintain the Product. Some examples of the kinds of
information we may passively collect include randomly assigned unique identifiers and other
information contained in browser cookies and “Flash” cookies or HTML5 local storage; Internet
Protocol address (“IP Address”); unique device identifiers; login information; session
information; device type; operating system type and version; browser software type and version;
timestamp information; screen resolution; Your browser software’s installed plug-ins; and other
technical or similar information.
Browser Cookies are small text files stored on Your device, which are transmitted to us when
You use our site. The use of cookies helps us understand how our site is used. Cookies help us to
improve content, navigation, and functionality. You can manage the placement of cookies on
Your device through the features found in most Internet browsers, including adjusting Your
browser settings to warn You before a cookie is stored or to block all cookies. Please be aware
that if You disable or remove cookies on Your device, some parts of our Product may not
function properly or may be completely disabled, and that when You revisit our Product, Your
ability to limit cookies is subject to Your browser software’s settings and limitations.
Flash Cookies and other Local Shared Objects, or “LSOs,” may be used in conjunction with
Adobe’s Flash Player and similar technology. They are typically used for functionality in video
and rich content, but they can also be used for analytics and many of the same purposes as
Browser Cookies. Flash Cookies and LSOs are not stored in the Browser. Information and a tool
to delete and manage Flash Cookies and LSOs may be found at
https://www.adobe.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html.
Web Beacons are very small image files that trigger the transmission of cookies or may be used
to collect IP Addresses. Web beacons and similar technologies are often used for analytics, to
count visitors to the site, to monitor how users use the Product, and for other related purposes.
3.       Information We Generate
We may de-identify and otherwise convert Usage Information and Submitted Data into De-
Identified Information.
                                                  2

4.      How We Use Information
Our Use of Personal Information. Our primary purpose in collecting information about You is
to provide You with the Product that You request and to operate the services that comprise the
Product. We may also decide to send You e-mails and other correspondence regarding the
Product, our site and other information and services that we believe may be of interest to You as
well as customer satisfaction surveys and requests for Feedback about our Product and site. You
may opt out from receiving certain communications by following the instructions provided at the
bottom of the communication. Please understand that You will not be able to opt out of formal
notices concerning the operation of our site, and legal and other related notices concerning Your
relationship with us, the site, and the Product.
Our Use of Usage Information. We use Usage Information to track how our site is used, or not
used, and to improve the functionality of our Products and services.
Our Use of De-Identified Information. HMH will only use De-Identified Information for
lawful purposes, including but not limited to, quality assurance, research, and/or test
development. HMH may de-identify Usage Information in accordance with HIPAA and FERPA,
and use this De-Identified Information to develop, evaluate, and provide improved educational
products and services, as permitted under HIPAA and FERPA.
5.      How We Share Information
We do not sell, rent, or license Your Personal Information to anyone. We do share Personal
Information with other companies in the following situations:
Sharing Your Information with Subcontractors. We may share information with
subcontractors that act as our agent and that provide us with services related to the provision or
operation of the Product. These services may include, among other things, helping us to provide
products or services that You request, creating or maintaining our databases, processing orders
and transactions, and other similar purposes. Any party with whom we share Your Personal
Information is required either contractually or by law to keep Your Personal Information
confidential and not to disclose or repurpose the information, and to use such information only as
required for the services to be performed.
Law Enforcement and Legal Process. We may disclose Personal Information to government
and regulatory agencies to comply with a court order or as otherwise required by applicable law.
Targeted Advertisers. We do not engage in interest-based advertising, also known as online
behavioral advertising, or “OBA,” with respect to Your use of this Product. We may, however,
provide contextual information, including contextual marketing or advertising that does not rely
on information about Your Internet browsing behavior.
6.      How We Protect Your Information
HMH shall implement and maintain for the Product information security controls that comply
with Relevant Information Security Standards.
                                                 3

7.      Links to Other Websites
We may provide links to third-party websites to provide information that may be of interest to
our users. If we provide links to third-party websites and You select a link to a third-party site,
please note that You are subject to the privacy and security policies of the third party who
controls or operates that site. We are not responsible for the security or protection of information
You provide to such third parties once You leave our site.
8.      How to Contact Us
If You have questions or concerns regarding this Policy, please contact us at
privacy@hmhco.com. If we need to contact You concerning any event that involves Your
information, we may do so by e-mail, telephone, or mail.
9.      Revisions
We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy at any time. Any changes or updates
become effective immediately upon posting of the change. Please check the revision date below
to determine whether there have been any changes since You have last reviewed our Privacy
Policy.
10.     Transfer of Ownership
We shall be entitled to transfer Submitted Data (including, but not limited to, Personal
Information) to a third party in connection with a sale of all or substantially all of the assets of
the entity responsible for the information under this Privacy Policy, provided the acquiring third
party has agreed to safeguard Your Submitted Data with protections that in all material respects
are the same as or more protective than those set out in this Privacy Policy.
11.     Do-Not-Track
Because We do not use online behavioral advertising as part of the Product, the website and any
online service associated with the Product do not change their behavior if and when they receive
a “Do-Not-Track” flag from browser software.
12.     Complete Agreement
This Privacy Policy must be read in conjunction with our Terms of Use, and the provisions of
our Terms of Use are incorporated herein. To the extent the Terms of Use conflict with the terms
of this Privacy Policy, the terms of this Privacy Policy shall control.
Effective Date: June 2014
                                                  4
